This book is for software developers who are interested in creating user interfaces for
Windows. Regardless of whether you’re creating line-of-business applications, consumerfacing
applications, or reusable controls, this book contains a lot of content that helps
you get the most out of the platform. It’s designed to be understandable even for folks
who are new to the .NET Framework. And if you are already well versed in WPF, I’m
confident that this book still has information for you. At the very least, it should be an
invaluable reference for your bookshelf.